all right everybody welcome to another
assembly tutorial in this tutorial I
want to go over how to define integers
and as well as how to make our
compilation process seamless and
integrated by using linux shell
scripting I have a tutorial on my
channel on how to do linux shell
scripting but if you want to go ahead
and pause the video and copy down this
script real quick it makes your life
easier otherwise you can just do what
we've been doing which is NSM - f and
you know all that jazz and then convert
it to you know by using the script I
just make it a little bit more easier
myself okay so this is this entire
script and its entirety okay back to our
assembly program now we're going to talk
about how to declare integers and assign
values to it and change values and then
as well as print out that value to the
screen to show what's going on okay so
let's get to it we're going to
front/back in our data section we're
going to define an a variable called I
and that variable is going to be a
double a double it's a defined double so
this is the basic breakdown of all these
types of keywords and net wide assembler
define byte is 8 bits so in other words
it's a byte define word a word is 16
bits okay and define double a double is
a 32 bits
so that's your integers and your floats
and this should be defined Q is should
be D Q which is a defined quadruple and
at 64 bits okay so in this case we're
declaring an integer and an integer if
you're familiar with C or C++ or Java
and in an integer is 32 bits in length
and so that's what we're doing here
we're going to say that this number is
this variable is going to be of size
double word so 120 okay so after we have
this we're also going to have a message
that's that says valley of my integer is
you know and then instead of this it's
going to replace it and we're going to
replace it with I and it should display
120 to the screen so let's go ahead and
print this out to the screen and we're
going to say of course usually by using
printf you want to have everything
displayed backwards so the format and
then the value that we want to print out
so to do this in assembly we would go
push the address of of the variable I if
you don't have this D word in front of I
the compiler or nasan will give you an
error telling you that you need to
specify a size so this keyword is
important otherwise it will give you an
error and what this effectively does is
remember the labels are treated as
memory address locations so therefore
this is actually a memory address so I
is standing in the place of let's say Oh
x8 AIDS you know that's that's what I is
it's a memory address so all this does
is push that memory address onto the
stack and next we're going to push the
message that we want to display and in
this case it's going to be format two
and then we're going to call printf and
that's it so let's go back to our
terminal and let's display this message
but first going to compile and it says
everything was successful and then we're
going to run our program and our sets
our integers but that means we made a
mistake so let's go back and see what
happened here
okay so the mistake is that here we're
pushing not we're not actually pushing
the value of I we're pushing its address
so what we have here compiled is again
and run it what we have here is the
address of I displayed in decimal format
as opposed to hexadecimal if we wanted
to display it in hexadecimal we just
type X here and go back and run so now
this is the address of I in hexadecimal
but that's something we want we want we
want the value 120 displayed to the
screen so therefore what we have to do
is change here into braces and and this
says instead of look at the memory
address and take its contents and push
it onto the stack so in this case this
is effectively pushing 120 onto the
stack and so let's compile this again
run it and as we can see it's 78 and 78
is hexadecimal for 120 and let's change
this back to Dean save our program
compile it again and run and as we can
see the value is 120 well that's it for
this tutorial in the next one we'll show
you how to work with if statements
remember to subscribe and rate this
video thank you